<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>architecture | Giuseppe Peronato</title>
    <link>/tag/architecture/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>architecture</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 17:03:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu9b267b0aefc2a2d4cc91bda64951c871_10671_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>architecture</title>
      <link>/tag/architecture/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Carving</title>
      <link>/project/citycarving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 17:03:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/citycarving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The theme of the studio was the design of high-density settlements in China using computational algorithms and parametric tools to generate shapes dynamically responding to external imputs (e.g. climate and topography) and custom parameters (e.g. number of inhabitants).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was based on the joint use of terraces and courtyards building typologies in order to design a city dealing with both the external landscape and a more intimate view inside the courtyard.
The terraced structure aims at recreating the hill shape by using the contour lines as the main design input. A network of walkways is set up to connect the plain to the top of the hill, starting from points where there is a main variation of the curvature of the contour line. The hill is hence subdivided in different sectors, with different expositions to the sun and different slopes. Courtyards are designed to provide as much sunlight as possible to the dwellings. This is accomplished by introducing a “C” shaped typology, where the opening is always South-facing, as well as by increasing the height only of North-facing buildings. Furthermore, different courtyard shapes are defined according to their orientation. Outwards facing sides have different degrees of openness, ranging from completely closed (North-facing) to fully opened (South-facing). Finally, the roof is stretched according to the orientation in order to direct as much sunlight as possible into the courtyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parametric workflow makes possible to transfer the design to other contexts as well as to easily increase the density while preserving all the design features.








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_2-3.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_2-3_huc1e80ae0c9bcd86703c5a52b0decfa0e_54538_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_model3.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_model3_hu9234be192dc78f911aa6f0e26aceffeb_115585_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_plan.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_plan_hu734fa4da54a50cae1db2c7710f6190ed_137500_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_section.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/citycarving/images/city-carving_section_hu6457ea6901abbf68b71068acd01e10c0_92976_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1058&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reuse-Recycle</title>
      <link>/project/ponte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 17:03:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ponte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not used for 50 years and partially dismissed in 1968, the railway bridge crossing the Astico river (Vicenza’s area, north-east of Italy) is now a phantom infrastructure. The bridge starts from the east side of the valley and is truncated after three masonry arcades, because of the removal of the steel truss that used to connect it to the other side of the valley.
Replaced by a new car bridge in the 70s, the sawn-off bridge is still a strong landmark that could be used to improve the touristic attractiveness of this area. The Astico valley is in fact an ideal place to practice water sports as well as hiking and cycling. The challenge of this project is the use of the bridge in a different way than its original function while recalling its past and preserving its iconic image of abandoned infra- structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old train car recently dismissed from a railway in Sardinia that was also the last train model riding on this bridge was readapted as an information center welcoming the visitor. The passenger car reminds the old railway while symbolizing the possibility of recycling an old object into another function. The whole valley section was set up as a climbing practice wall with different difficulty degrees. The most trained climbers could reach the old railway tunnel, reused as a panoramic rest area. On the right side of the valley, a panoramic path leads to the valley bottom with equipped beaches and a natural swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architectural project fits in with the bridge as a parasite element, breaking the strict regularity of the historical artefact. The first arcade hosts some practice walls for children rock climbing, while the second one is crossed by the flying footbridge going to the 200 m2 bar-restaurant area located under the third arcade. The envelope of the restaurant is composed by the masonry pillars of the bridge on the South and North sides and by a new curtain wall on the East and West sides, designed so as to minimize the heat gains in summer.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_dalle_vasche.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_dalle_vasche_hu39315aedc075fe92e123faaca4f7e830_578790_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_plastico1.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_plastico1_hu33dfffc6be14b5ab01faf14a874f0dac_254465_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_plastico2.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_plastico2_hud6f22bf1c7b27aafb74af99bb5c9a34b_138030_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_sezione.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/ponte/images/astico_sezione_hu7c88814a9f8191158dbb1a976acc7c54_68457_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;424&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-images&#34; href=&#34;/project/ponte/images/dalla_passerella.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/project/ponte/images/dalla_passerella_hu9f0b4d870e819cc8b4d2208abaa681d0_467761_0x300_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;417&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
